<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Kernel Security, Isolation, and Verification (KISV) Workshop on KISV Workshop</title>
    <link>https://kisv-workshop.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Kernel Security, Isolation, and Verification (KISV) Workshop on KISV Workshop</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://kisv-workshop.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Organizers</title>
      <link>https://kisv-workshop.github.io/organizers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kisv-workshop.github.io/organizers/</guid>
      <description>Anton Burtsev, University of Utah
Vikram Narayanan, University of Utah
Program Committee Nathan Burow, MIT Lincoln Laboratory
Nathan Dautenhahn, Rice University
Trent Jaeger, Pennsylvania State University
Shravan Narayan, University of Texas, Austin
Ruslan Nikolaev, Pennsylvania State University
Pierre Olivier, University of Manchester
Gerd Zellweger, VMware Research</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Anton Burtsev</strong>, University of Utah</p>
<p><strong>Vikram Narayanan</strong>, University of Utah</p>
<h2 id="program-committee">Program Committee</h2>
<p>Nathan Burow, MIT Lincoln Laboratory</p>
<p>Nathan Dautenhahn, Rice University</p>
<p>Trent Jaeger, Pennsylvania State University</p>
<p>Shravan Narayan, University of Texas, Austin</p>
<p>Ruslan Nikolaev, Pennsylvania State University</p>
<p>Pierre Olivier, University of Manchester</p>
<p>Gerd Zellweger, VMware Research</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Program</title>
      <link>https://kisv-workshop.github.io/program/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kisv-workshop.github.io/program/</guid>
      <description>Accepted papers The following papers will be presented at KISV 2023. We will replace this list with the complete program shortly.
Encapsulated Functions: Fortifying Rust’s FFI in Embedded Systems. Leon Schuermann (Princeton University), Amit Levy (Princeton University), Arun Thomas (zeroRISC Inc.)
Leveraging Rust for Lightweight OS Correctness. Ramla Ijaz (Yale University), Kevin Boos (Theseus Systems), Lin Zhong (Yale University)
CIVSCOPE: Analyzing Potential Memory Corruption Bugs in Compartment Interfaces by Establishing Lower Bound and Upper Bound.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2 id="accepted-papers">Accepted papers</h2>
<p>The following papers will be presented at KISV 2023. We will replace this list
with the complete program shortly.</p>
<ul>
<li>
<p><strong>Encapsulated Functions: Fortifying Rust’s FFI in Embedded Systems.</strong> Leon
Schuermann (Princeton University), Amit Levy (Princeton University), Arun
Thomas (zeroRISC Inc.)</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Leveraging Rust for Lightweight OS Correctness.</strong> Ramla Ijaz (Yale
University), Kevin Boos (Theseus Systems), Lin Zhong (Yale University)</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>CIVSCOPE: Analyzing Potential Memory Corruption Bugs in Compartment
Interfaces by Establishing Lower Bound and Upper Bound.</strong>
Yi Chien (Rice University), Vlad-Andrei Bădoiu (University Politehnica of
Bucharest), Yudi Yang (Rice University), Yuqian Huo (Rice University), Kelly
Kaoudis (Trail of Bits), Hugo Lefeuvre (The University of Manchester), Pierre
Olivier (The University of Manchester), Nathan Dautenhahn (Rice University)</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Specifying the de-facto OS of a production SoC.</strong> Ben Fiedler (ETH Zurich),
Roman Meier (ETH Zurich), Jasmin Schult (ETH Zurich), Daniel Schwyn (ETH
Zurich), Timothy Roscoe (ETH Zurich)</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Atmosphere: Towards Practical Verified Kernels in Rust.</strong> Xiangdong Chen
(University of Utah), Zhaofeng Li (University of Utah), Vikram Narayanan
(University of Utah), Anton Burtsev (University of Utah)</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>The K2 Architecture for Modular Hardware Security Modules.</strong> Anish Athalye
(MIT), Frans Kaashoek (MIT), Nickolai Zeldovich (MIT), Joseph Tassarotti (New
York University)</p>
</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
